

FRONT END ENGINEER

Sofokleous 34, Nikaia, Athens, Greece, 18452

□ (+30) 6949413084 | Salexandra2@gmail.com | Aale3oula.github.io | Salexabarka@hotmail.com

Summary _____

I am a **Front End Engineer** with experience on building software and web applications. I enjoy creating **simple**, **clean** and **creative** user interfaces using the latest web technologies. I specialize in JavaScript and have professional experience working with Angular 2+. I also have adequate experience working with WPF (C#) and Node.js. Currently, I am focusing on further developing my skills in Angular 7 and learning Vue.

Skills

Web HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (ES2015+), TypeScript

JS Frameworks Angular 2+, Vue.js, Angular Ionic, Devextreme

Other Frameworks Bootstrap (CSS), Node.JS

Programming C, C#, JAVA

Applications Visual Studio Code, Intellij

Other Microsoft Office, Pages, Keynote, Adobe Suite, Figma

Experience _____

UBITECH Ltd.Athens, Greece

UX ENGINEER Jul. 2018 - Today

• Working in several projects using several web technologies (Angular 7, Vue.js, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Thymeleaf). My responsibilities include creating front end components and services by using the best practices and integrating with a REST API.

• Technologies used: Angular 2+, JavaScript, TypeScript, Thymeleaf, AngularJS, HTML5, CSS3

Human Computer Interaction Laboratory - ICS FORTH)

Heraklion, Crete

RESEARCH ASSISTANT - UI/UX ENGINEER

Jul. 2015 - Jul. 2018

- **Ulnify.** A full stack application (MEAN stack: Mongo.DB, Express.js, Angular 6, Node.js)which acted as a studio for composing flexible web applications in real-time and aggregate all the individual UIs of an intelligent environment by introducing new rich user interface compositions.
- **Beantable.** Co-develop an augmented interactive table with multiple games for the Heraklion Public Library of Crete. Used C# and WPF to implement a launcher for the application and re-design various games (e.g. puzzle, classic memory games).
- Arkadi Monastery. Re-design and develop a mobile application for the Arkadi Museum in Rethimni. Used Actionscript and Adobe Flash Builder to implement a cross-platform application for both Android and iOS. [link]
- Info kiosk. Co-developed an info kiosk for the Archeological Museum of Crete, which provided information for the Minoan Culture. Developed in C# and WPF the Architecture section and some Utilities.
- Technologies used: Angular 2+, MEAN stack, WPF, C#, Actionscript, Typescript, Javacript, Node.js HTML/CSS

Education _____

University of Crete, Dpt. of Computer Science

Heraklion, Crete

 $\mathsf{M.Sc.}$ in Information Systems and HCI

Feb. 2016 - Nov. 2018

- Grade: 9.28 / 10
- Coursework included Introduction and advanced topics on HCI, Information Retrieval, DBMS, BPMS and Knowledge Representation and Reasoning. Teaching Assistant in Introduction on HCI (Spring 2018), Modern Topics on HCI (Winter 2017) and Data Structures (2016-2017).
- Thesis Topic: Ulnify: A Designer Studio for creating UI Mashups for Ambient Intelligence Environments.
- Supervisor: Stephanidis Constantine

University of Crete, Dpt. of Computer Science

Heraklion, Crete

B.Sc. in Computer Science Sep. 2011 - Jan. 2016

- Grade: 8.19 / 10
- Coursework included HCI, Web programming, Data Structures, Compilers, Algorithms and Complexity and more. Volunteered as a TA in Computer Organisation and Introduction to C programming coursed.
- Undergraduate TA in CS-225 Computer Organization.
- Undergraduate TA in CS-100 Introduction in Computer Science.
- Thesis Topic: Requirements analysis and development of conceptual model of an information system for food traceability
- Supervisors: Fountoulaki Irini, Plexousakis Dimitris

Publications _

womENcourage 2017 Conference

Barcelona, Spain

A Unified Interactive System for Controlling a Smart Home - Alexandra Barka, Asterios Leonidis,

Sep. 2016

MARGHERITA ANTONA, CONSTANTINE STEPHANIDIS

- Poster presentation at the ACM-W conference held in Barcelona, Spain
- ACM Scholarship to participate the conference

Volunteer _

womENcourage 2017

Heraklion, Crete

Website management Spring 2017

• Update, adding content and managing ACM - Womencourage website (Wordpress): https://womencourage.acm.org/2017/

Undergraduate Teaching Assistant

Heraklion, Crete

Winter 2015

CS 100 - Introduction to Computer Science

- · Answering questions on the mailing list.
- Co-assist in two tutorials.

Heraklion, Crete

Spring 2015

Undergraduate Teaching Assistant

CS 225 - COMPUTER ORGANIZATION

- Answering questions on the mailing list.
- · Oral examination of two assignment.
- Marking examination scripts.

Teaching Assistance

Graduate Teaching Assistant

Heraklion, Crete

CS 364 - Introduction to Human-Computer Interaction

Spring 2017

- · Answering questions on the mailing list.
- Examining course projects
- Marking examinations transcripts

Graduate Teaching Assistant

Heraklion, Crete

CS 469 - MODERN TOPICS IN HUMAN-COMPUTER INTERACTION

Winter 2017

- Answering questions on the mailing list.
- · Lab course for Web accessibility
- Examining course projects

Graduate Teaching Assistant

Heraklion, Crete

CS 240 - DATA STRUCTURES

Winter 2016 - Spring 2017

Responsible for the website and the web infrastructure of the course.

- Answering questions on the mailing list.
- Marking examinations transcripts

June 6, 2019 Alexandra Barka · Résumé

Graduate Teaching Assistant

Heraklion, Crete

CS 240 - DATA STRUCTURES Spring 2016

- Project co-design with another TA.
- Answering questions on the mailing list.
- Marking examinations transcripts

Languages _____

ENGLISH

2007 First Certificate in English (B2), Cambridge University

В